<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ansible on rob's blog</title><link>https://blog.reb.gg/tags/ansible/</link><description>Recent content in Ansible on rob's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Rob Herley</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.reb.gg/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🏡 Homelab IV: Proxmox Dynamic Inventory and LXC Templates</title><link>https://blog.reb.gg/posts/04-homelab-pt4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.reb.gg/posts/04-homelab-pt4/</guid><description>In the previous part of this series, I configured Ansible and made some basic playbooks for the homelab management. Eventually, I&amp;rsquo;ll be deploying a plethora of VMs and containers, but managing a gigantic inventory every time a guest is spun up/down would be a hassle. Fortunately, there are community plugins for Ansible that allow the use of a Proxmox cluster as a dynamic inventory.
In this part, I&amp;rsquo;ll setup some Proxmox API users for automation, setup a dynamic inventory for Proxmox guests and prepare a template for Linux containers.</description></item><item><title>🏡 Homelab III: Automation with Ansible and Hardening Access</title><link>https://blog.reb.gg/posts/03-homelab-pt3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.reb.gg/posts/03-homelab-pt3/</guid><description>In the previous part of this series, I created a two-node Proxmox cluster along with redundant (ZFS) and shared (NFS) storage. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;ll go over how to connect to the host machines with Ansible, harden access, and setup some minor user management. This&amp;rsquo;ll all be through an automatic, idempotent configuration process.
# What is Ansible? Ansible is a great automation platform from Red Hat (they bought AnsibleWorks), and it&amp;rsquo;s an extremely popular tool making it a great learning exercise for the homelab.</description></item></channel></rss>